<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jamie J Quinn</title><link>https://example.com/</link><description>Recent content on Jamie J Quinn</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-GB</language><copyright>Copyright © 2024, Jamie J Quinn.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Converting C437 to XNA-style Spritesheets</title><link>https://example.com/converting-c437-to-xna-style-spritesheets/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/converting-c437-to-xna-style-spritesheets/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling to get C437 PNG fonts loaded in Raylib due to its default PNG loader using a slightly different format. Here, I&amp;rsquo;ll detail a simple way of converting C437 PNGs to the format Raylib expects.
Raylib is a wonderful library for writing quick and simple GUI applications, especially games. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it for about a year on various prototypes, most recently a roguelike in Zig. While Raylib&amp;rsquo;s text rendering is generally good, I wanted to be able to use old-school fonts using the Code page 437 character set.</description></item><item><title>Principles for Automated and Reproducible Benchmarking</title><link>https://example.com/publications/2023_sc23/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/publications/2023_sc23/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Years as a trustee of SocRSE UK; A retrospective</title><link>https://example.com/presentations/2023_rse_retrospective/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/presentations/2023_rse_retrospective/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Xclim; xarray-based climate data</title><link>https://example.com/publications/2023_xclim/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/publications/2023_xclim/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Role of Heterogeneous Computing on the Expressway to Net Zero Compute</title><link>https://example.com/presentations/2023_power_efficient_hpc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/presentations/2023_power_efficient_hpc/</guid><description/></item><item><title>An Introduction to FPGAs</title><link>https://example.com/presentations/2022_fpgas_excalibur/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/presentations/2022_fpgas_excalibur/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Flute and kink instabilities in a dynamically twisted flux tube with anisotropic plasma viscosity</title><link>https://example.com/publications/2021_khi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/publications/2021_khi/</guid><description/></item><item><title>GPU-Accelerated Spectral Methods in Python; A Case Study</title><link>https://example.com/presentations/2021_melvin_septembrse/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/presentations/2021_melvin_septembrse/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Kelvin-Helmholtz instability and collapse of a twisted magnetic null point with anisotropic viscosity</title><link>https://example.com/publications/2022_flute_instability/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/publications/2022_flute_instability/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Accelerated Python for CFD</title><link>https://example.com/presentations/2021-scot-fluid-melvin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/presentations/2021-scot-fluid-melvin/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Analysing the prevalence of continuous integration in JOSS</title><link>https://example.com/analysing-the-prevalence-of-continuous-integration-in-joss/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 18:42:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/analysing-the-prevalence-of-continuous-integration-in-joss/</guid><description>JOSS is the Journal of Open Source Software and can be considered a collection of some excellent scientific codebases. Whether they&amp;rsquo;re exemplars of good coding practices is up for debate but I wanted to know roughly how many published papers (and associated codebases) were using specifically continuous integration of some form. Luckily I have some experience scraping web pages with python and the excellent webscraping package BeautifulSoup, so I cracked out the old tutorials and set to work.</description></item><item><title>Four pillars of a reproducible PhD</title><link>https://example.com/four-pillars-of-a-reproducible-phd/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 13:07:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/four-pillars-of-a-reproducible-phd/</guid><description>As the academic community continues to embrace open science and reproducible research, it is increasingly important for an academic to understand the tools which can make research easier, more accessible and more sustainable. It can be challenging to absorb so many different good practices while still getting research done. However, I would argue that anything helps. While all good practices in open science are important, even just incorporating one example is good for the community, and provides a solid personal foundation for gradually incorporating more good practices.</description></item><item><title>How to Render Latex in Inkscape</title><link>https://example.com/how-to-render-latex-in-inkscape/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 16:45:05 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/how-to-render-latex-in-inkscape/</guid><description>Rendering latex equations or text in the graphics package Inkscape is not an intuitive task, so I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to create an extremely short tutorial on doing exactly that using Inkscape&amp;rsquo;s in-built latex extesion. It&amp;rsquo;s not difficult but the menus are quite cluttered and there&amp;rsquo;s a quirk to rendering to equations that&amp;rsquo;s helpful to know.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always found the default extension sufficient but if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a more polished experience, check out TexText.</description></item><item><title>The effect of anisotropic viscosity on the nonlinear MHD kink instability</title><link>https://example.com/publications/2020_kink_instability/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/publications/2020_kink_instability/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The effect of anisotropic viscosity on the nonlinear kink instability</title><link>https://example.com/presentations/2019-st-andrews-mhd-seminar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/presentations/2019-st-andrews-mhd-seminar/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hot Stuff; An Introduction to Magnetohydrodynamics</title><link>https://example.com/presentations/2018-pg-mhd-seminar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/presentations/2018-pg-mhd-seminar/</guid><description/></item><item><title>An Implementation of the Switching Model of Anisotropic Viscosity in Lare3d</title><link>https://example.com/presentations/2019-nam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/presentations/2019-nam/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Stairway to Haline</title><link>https://example.com/presentations/2019-stairway-to-haline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/presentations/2019-stairway-to-haline/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Effect of Anisotropic Viscosity on the Nonlinear Kink Instability</title><link>https://example.com/presentations/2019-loops/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/presentations/2019-loops/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Finally, a strong, Abel woman</title><link>https://example.com/finally-a-strong-abel-woman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 20:16:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/finally-a-strong-abel-woman/</guid><description>Just this month the Abel prize, commonly considered to be the Nobel prize of mathematics, was awarded to the first female prizewinner, Karen Keskulla Uhlenbeck. Now a professor emeritus at the University of Texas, and a visiting associate at the Institute for Advanced Study, Uhlenbeck&amp;rsquo;s work has had a profound impact on many areas of mathematics, with implications in theoretical physics.
Despite describing Einstein&amp;rsquo;s general relativity as &amp;ldquo;too hard&amp;rdquo;, in a single paper, Uhlenbeck is considered to have founded the field of geometric analysis, a mathematical discipline that mixes differential geometry (an extremely technical way of describing and analysing the nature of spaces) and differential equations (types of complicated equations that can describe the flow of water, the evolution of bacteria and fluctuations in the stock market).</description></item><item><title>UGRacing Ahead</title><link>https://example.com/ugracing-ahead/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 20:16:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/ugracing-ahead/</guid><description>Just a short while ago I had the pleasure of spending an afternoon with the University of Glasgow Racing team, found either in their cosy, computer filled office in the James Watt South, or nestled in their garage, deep in the bowels of the Rankine. Chatting with Oliver, team principal, Kester, head engineer, and Callum, a team member, they introduced me to the team&amp;rsquo;s current progress as they design, test and manufacture a working racing car, all with the goal of competing in Formula Student.</description></item><item><title>Applications of an Anisotropic Viscous Stress Tensor to Coronal Heating</title><link>https://example.com/presentations/2019-siam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/presentations/2019-siam/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Mathematics of Synthesis</title><link>https://example.com/presentations/2018-maths-of-synthesis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/presentations/2018-maths-of-synthesis/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ansiotropic Viscosity; How Runny is the Sun?</title><link>https://example.com/presentations/2019-3-minute-thesis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/presentations/2019-3-minute-thesis/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Not so elementary, Dr Watson</title><link>https://example.com/not-so-elementary-dr-watson/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 20:33:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/not-so-elementary-dr-watson/</guid><description>Why do clever people say dumb things? How is it that incredibly well-known, well-respected minds that have forged today’s world through scientific rigor and raw intellectual power, can end up thinking that because you’re black, you’re less intelligent?
Surely a renowned geneticist, a Nobel laureate at that, wouldn’t say something totally unsubstantiated like, “there’s a difference on the average between blacks and whites on IQ tests. I would say the difference is, it’s genetic.</description></item><item><title>Illegal? No, not in China</title><link>https://example.com/illegal-no-not-in-china/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 20:36:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/illegal-no-not-in-china/</guid><description>The recent news from China of a genetically altered pair of twins is frightening. He Jiankui, from the Southern University of Science and Technology of China, genetically altered the DNA of multiple embryos using the gene-editing technique CRISPR in order to disable the CCR5 gene, thought to be responsible for vulnerability to HIV.
Disable the gene in a person and they can be theoretically immune to the disease. This sounds like a wonderful use of modern technology, allowing people with HIV to safely have children.</description></item><item><title>The falsehood of the PhD pedestal</title><link>https://example.com/the-falsehood-of-the-phd-pedestal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 20:40:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/the-falsehood-of-the-phd-pedestal/</guid><description>The British government, in introducing the new doctoral loans offered to graduates aiming for a PhD, have sent out a message – “PhDs are valuable”. This stinks of the same misguided and ill-considered ambition of Tony Blair, who, almost 20 years ago set out his grand ambition to have at least half of the entire young population of Britain entered into higher education by 2010. In a feat of remarkable cross-party agreement, that goal was reached, and yet the UK is not better off for it.</description></item><item><title>UofG; Students' Representative Council</title><link>https://example.com/presentations/2018-china/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/presentations/2018-china/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Herd immunity and why it matters</title><link>https://example.com/herd-immunity-and-why-it-matters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 20:43:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/herd-immunity-and-why-it-matters/</guid><description>We’ve all encountered someone in our lives that’s been royally freaked out by vaccinations. Be it a friend who just can’t stand needles or a hardcore anti-vaxxer, a certain fear of vaccinations exists in our society and the deadly consequences of this fear have been growing. We’re all in our own ways susceptible to the scare-tactics rolled out by the anti-vaccination lobbyists. When vaccinating my sister, my own parents were swept up in the MMR scandal, that anti-expert foreshadowing moment when disgraced doctor Andrew Wakefield convinced the entire country that the combined MMR jag could cause autism in children.</description></item><item><title>Running Fluid Simulations in WebGL I - Simple Convection</title><link>https://example.com/running-fluid-simulations-in-webgl-i-simple-convection/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/running-fluid-simulations-in-webgl-i-simple-convection/</guid><description>Years ago I worked my way through Lorena Barba&amp;rsquo;s 12 steps to Navier-Stokes in Python, but recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting more and more into GPU programming and figured that it would be an interesting exercise to redo the steps in WebGL. Really when I say GPU programming I mean using general purpose tech like CUDA, but CUDA and WebGL are similar enough (the boilerplate is of course totally different but the idea of writing a kernel to act on many pixels/fluid cells is the same).</description></item><item><title>Radiosity; Global Illumination in Computer Graphics</title><link>https://example.com/presentations/2017-radiosity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/presentations/2017-radiosity/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mr. Julia</title><link>https://example.com/mr.-julia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/mr.-julia/</guid><description>Going on my theme of wonderfully fractal images, I wrote a little simulation to introduce myself to webGL. Go have a wee play about with it here.
The Maths You can find lots of information about Julia fractals all around the web so I won&amp;rsquo;t go into much detail at all here. All I&amp;rsquo;ll say is that the fractals, named for Gaston Julia, come about by iterating a complex number through the formula $$z_{n+1} = z_n^2 + c,$$ where \(c\) is some complex number.</description></item><item><title>Braginskii magnetohydrodynamics for arbitrary magnetic topologies; coronal applications</title><link>https://example.com/publications/2017_braginskii/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/publications/2017_braginskii/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Regularly Expressional Fractalations</title><link>https://example.com/regularly-expressional-fractalations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/regularly-expressional-fractalations/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s something about fractals that humans find fascinating. They manage to contain a beautiful impression of infinity despite being not very difficult to create. These fractals have been produced by a very simple recipe:
Split a big square of pixels into 4 quadrants and label them 1 to 4 Repeat this process for each of the smaller squares and add the quadrant number to the label Keep cutting the squares into 4 until you&amp;rsquo;ve gone as small as you want Now we can use regular expressions to find and mark boxes with certain labels I wrote a little bit of javascript that creates such fractals from regular expressions involving the digits 1, 2, 3 or 4.</description></item><item><title>How I lost a Day to OpenMPI Being Mental</title><link>https://example.com/how-i-lost-a-day-to-openmpi-being-mental/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 13:28:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/how-i-lost-a-day-to-openmpi-being-mental/</guid><description>So at Glasgow Uni we have this little cluster for the maths department which happens to including about ten machines set up to work with torque (a job scheduling system). I discovered that these machines hadn&amp;rsquo;t had anything run on them for literally months, what a waste of resources! To rectify this atrocity I decided to try and run my MPI enabled code on all ten machines.
Problem One Turns out two of the machines have eight cores and the other eight have twelve cores.</description></item><item><title>4 Tips on Making Simulations Bug Resistant</title><link>https://example.com/4-tips-on-making-simulations-bug-resistant/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/4-tips-on-making-simulations-bug-resistant/</guid><description>Having written and used a decent number of simulations over the past few years I&amp;rsquo;ve come to understand that preventing bugs in scientific software is just a wee bit different from how it&amp;rsquo;s usually done in more standard software development.
For one thing, many of the simulations come under the category of high performance computing (HPC) simulations, so it can take a long time to build and run a test case, leading to iteration speeds that are painfully slow.</description></item><item><title>Anisotropic Viscosity in MHD; Heating Profiles About Coronal Null Points</title><link>https://example.com/presentations/2017-ukmhd/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/presentations/2017-ukmhd/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Parallelising Wondrous Numbers in C++</title><link>https://example.com/parallelising-wondrous-numbers-in-c-/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/parallelising-wondrous-numbers-in-c-/</guid><description>The Collatz conjecture, named for Lothar Collatz, goes as follows.
Take any positive integer \(n\). If \(n\) is even, half it, or if it&amp;rsquo;s odd, multiply it by three and add one. Repeating the process will always bring you back to 1.
The sequence of numbers generated by repeating the process is sometimes called the hailstone sequence due to the strange way the sequence bounces around, as you can see below if we start the sequence at 19.</description></item><item><title>Mathematics in Art</title><link>https://example.com/presentations/2017-math-in-art/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/presentations/2017-math-in-art/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Making of the Fiddle Synth I</title><link>https://example.com/the-making-of-the-fiddle-synth-i/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/the-making-of-the-fiddle-synth-i/</guid><description>My idea for a violin synthesizer came about from a Lau concert I recently went to.
Before the concert there were a few different workshops, one of which was a synthesizer making workshop run by Martin Green, the accordion player from Lau. Unfortunately I didn&amp;rsquo;t make it along, but I did manage to see the concert where he uses synthesizers in just the right places to create an amazing deep sound.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up This Site</title><link>https://example.com/setting-up-this-site/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/setting-up-this-site/</guid><description>First there was a purely html site. I was about eleven.
Then, there was the Wordpress blog (or maybe Blogger). I was probably about thirteen.
After that came the social networks, Myspace, Bebo, Twitter, Facebook and Instagram, and then I decided I needed an actual blog for some reason. In my naivety I went for a full blown CMS stack, Mezzanine, a Django project. It took about a week solid, buying server space, setting up the entire site, finding a theme, tweaking the theme, breaking the theme, etc.</description></item><item><title>Jacobi Microbenchmark</title><link>https://example.com/projects/jacobi_microbenchmark/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:01:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/jacobi_microbenchmark/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Melvin.py</title><link>https://example.com/projects/melvin.py/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:01:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/melvin.py/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Radiosity Renderer</title><link>https://example.com/projects/radiosity_renderer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:01:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/radiosity_renderer/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dirac Cluster Challenge</title><link>https://example.com/projects/dirac_cluster_challenge/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:01:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/dirac_cluster_challenge/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Field Line Integrator</title><link>https://example.com/projects/field_line_integrator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:01:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/field_line_integrator/</guid><description/></item><item><title>FPGA-Accelerated Fluid Solver (FAFS)</title><link>https://example.com/projects/fafs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:01:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/fafs/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lare1d</title><link>https://example.com/projects/lare1d/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:01:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/lare1d/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lare3d</title><link>https://example.com/projects/lare3d/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:01:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/lare3d/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Melvin</title><link>https://example.com/projects/melvin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:01:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/melvin/</guid><description/></item><item><title>PyCascadia</title><link>https://example.com/projects/pycascadia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:01:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/pycascadia/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bytebeat</title><link>https://example.com/projects/bytebeat/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:01:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/bytebeat/</guid><description/></item><item><title>GFP Simulator 9000</title><link>https://example.com/projects/gfp_simulator_9000/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:01:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/gfp_simulator_9000/</guid><description/></item><item><title>IR-GTS</title><link>https://example.com/projects/ir_gts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/ir_gts/</guid><description/></item><item><title>JOSS Scraper</title><link>https://example.com/projects/joss_scraper/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/joss_scraper/</guid><description/></item><item><title>SDF Tool</title><link>https://example.com/projects/sdf_tool/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/sdf_tool/</guid><description/></item><item><title>4 Lines</title><link>https://example.com/projects/4_lines/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/4_lines/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Double Pendulum</title><link>https://example.com/projects/double_pendulum/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/double_pendulum/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lorenz Attractor</title><link>https://example.com/projects/lorenz_attractor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/lorenz_attractor/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Regex Fractals</title><link>https://example.com/projects/regex_fractals/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/regex_fractals/</guid><description/></item><item><title>WebGL Julia Fractal</title><link>https://example.com/projects/julia_fractals/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/julia_fractals/</guid><description/></item><item><title>GeorgeGL</title><link>https://example.com/projects/george_gl/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/george_gl/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Modelling anisotropic viscosity with applications in the solar corona</title><link>https://example.com/projects/thesis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/thesis/</guid><description/></item><item><title>True Ross Facts</title><link>https://example.com/projects/true_ross_facts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/true_ross_facts/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Collatz Conjecture</title><link>https://example.com/projects/collatz_conjecture/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/collatz_conjecture/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Anisotropic Viscosity Analysis</title><link>https://example.com/projects/anisotropic_viscosity_analysis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/anisotropic_viscosity_analysis/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Fluting Instability Analysis</title><link>https://example.com/projects/fluting_instability_analysis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/fluting_instability_analysis/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Kelvin-Helmholtz Instability Analysis</title><link>https://example.com/projects/khi_paper_analysis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/projects/khi_paper_analysis/</guid><description/></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://example.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/about/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved computer systems. Building PCs, networking them together and setting up servers and chat bots for friends was a key part of being a teenager for me. Of course I was interested in hacking as well; which wee nerd isn&amp;rsquo;t. Luckily I stopped being interested after gaining some useful skills but before getting into any (serious) trouble. I eventually got into programming through playing with Arduino boards, a great introduction to both basic electronics and low-level embedded programming.</description></item></channel></rss>