<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Glasgowguardian on Jamie J Quinn</title><link>https://example.com/tags/glasgowguardian/</link><description>Recent content in Glasgowguardian on Jamie J Quinn</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-GB</language><copyright>Copyright © 2024, Jamie J Quinn.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 20:16:48 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/tags/glasgowguardian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Finally, a strong, Abel woman</title><link>https://example.com/finally-a-strong-abel-woman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 20:16:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/finally-a-strong-abel-woman/</guid><description>Just this month the Abel prize, commonly considered to be the Nobel prize of mathematics, was awarded to the first female prizewinner, Karen Keskulla Uhlenbeck. Now a professor emeritus at the University of Texas, and a visiting associate at the Institute for Advanced Study, Uhlenbeck&amp;rsquo;s work has had a profound impact on many areas of mathematics, with implications in theoretical physics.
Despite describing Einstein&amp;rsquo;s general relativity as &amp;ldquo;too hard&amp;rdquo;, in a single paper, Uhlenbeck is considered to have founded the field of geometric analysis, a mathematical discipline that mixes differential geometry (an extremely technical way of describing and analysing the nature of spaces) and differential equations (types of complicated equations that can describe the flow of water, the evolution of bacteria and fluctuations in the stock market).</description></item><item><title>UGRacing Ahead</title><link>https://example.com/ugracing-ahead/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 20:16:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/ugracing-ahead/</guid><description>Just a short while ago I had the pleasure of spending an afternoon with the University of Glasgow Racing team, found either in their cosy, computer filled office in the James Watt South, or nestled in their garage, deep in the bowels of the Rankine. Chatting with Oliver, team principal, Kester, head engineer, and Callum, a team member, they introduced me to the team&amp;rsquo;s current progress as they design, test and manufacture a working racing car, all with the goal of competing in Formula Student.</description></item><item><title>Not so elementary, Dr Watson</title><link>https://example.com/not-so-elementary-dr-watson/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 20:33:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/not-so-elementary-dr-watson/</guid><description>Why do clever people say dumb things? How is it that incredibly well-known, well-respected minds that have forged today’s world through scientific rigor and raw intellectual power, can end up thinking that because you’re black, you’re less intelligent?
Surely a renowned geneticist, a Nobel laureate at that, wouldn’t say something totally unsubstantiated like, “there’s a difference on the average between blacks and whites on IQ tests. I would say the difference is, it’s genetic.</description></item><item><title>Illegal? No, not in China</title><link>https://example.com/illegal-no-not-in-china/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 20:36:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/illegal-no-not-in-china/</guid><description>The recent news from China of a genetically altered pair of twins is frightening. He Jiankui, from the Southern University of Science and Technology of China, genetically altered the DNA of multiple embryos using the gene-editing technique CRISPR in order to disable the CCR5 gene, thought to be responsible for vulnerability to HIV.
Disable the gene in a person and they can be theoretically immune to the disease. This sounds like a wonderful use of modern technology, allowing people with HIV to safely have children.</description></item><item><title>The falsehood of the PhD pedestal</title><link>https://example.com/the-falsehood-of-the-phd-pedestal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 20:40:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/the-falsehood-of-the-phd-pedestal/</guid><description>The British government, in introducing the new doctoral loans offered to graduates aiming for a PhD, have sent out a message – “PhDs are valuable”. This stinks of the same misguided and ill-considered ambition of Tony Blair, who, almost 20 years ago set out his grand ambition to have at least half of the entire young population of Britain entered into higher education by 2010. In a feat of remarkable cross-party agreement, that goal was reached, and yet the UK is not better off for it.</description></item><item><title>Herd immunity and why it matters</title><link>https://example.com/herd-immunity-and-why-it-matters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 20:43:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/herd-immunity-and-why-it-matters/</guid><description>We’ve all encountered someone in our lives that’s been royally freaked out by vaccinations. Be it a friend who just can’t stand needles or a hardcore anti-vaxxer, a certain fear of vaccinations exists in our society and the deadly consequences of this fear have been growing. We’re all in our own ways susceptible to the scare-tactics rolled out by the anti-vaccination lobbyists. When vaccinating my sister, my own parents were swept up in the MMR scandal, that anti-expert foreshadowing moment when disgraced doctor Andrew Wakefield convinced the entire country that the combined MMR jag could cause autism in children.</description></item></channel></rss>