<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Art on Jamie J Quinn</title><link>https://jamiejquinn.com/tags/art/</link><description>Recent content in Art on Jamie J Quinn</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-GB</language><copyright>Copyright © 2024, Jamie J Quinn.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jamiejquinn.com/tags/art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mr. Julia</title><link>https://jamiejquinn.com/mr.-julia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jamiejquinn.com/mr.-julia/</guid><description>Going on my theme of wonderfully fractal images, I wrote a little simulation to introduce myself to webGL. Go have a wee play about with it here.
The Maths You can find lots of information about Julia fractals all around the web so I won&amp;rsquo;t go into much detail at all here. All I&amp;rsquo;ll say is that the fractals, named for Gaston Julia, come about by iterating a complex number through the formula $$z_{n+1} = z_n^2 + c,$$ where \(c\) is some complex number.</description></item><item><title>Regularly Expressional Fractalations</title><link>https://jamiejquinn.com/regularly-expressional-fractalations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jamiejquinn.com/regularly-expressional-fractalations/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s something about fractals that humans find fascinating. They manage to contain a beautiful impression of infinity despite being not very difficult to create. These fractals have been produced by a very simple recipe:
Split a big square of pixels into 4 quadrants and label them 1 to 4 Repeat this process for each of the smaller squares and add the quadrant number to the label Keep cutting the squares into 4 until you&amp;rsquo;ve gone as small as you want Now we can use regular expressions to find and mark boxes with certain labels I wrote a little bit of javascript that creates such fractals from regular expressions involving the digits 1, 2, 3 or 4.</description></item></channel></rss>